Dumbgeons and Dragons will begin in a moment.
The heavy front doors open without resistance to the
Lingersville Academy.
Warm afternoon light spills across the polished wooden
floors untouched by dust.
Rows of neatly hung student coats line one wall.
Umbrella stands remain full.
A large slate chalkboard dominates the entrance hall.
Written in perfect white chalk are the words, welcome students.
Visitors, please await classification.
Attendance begins shortly.
Fresh chalk rests neatly on the tray below.
A polished brass bell hangs beside the board.
It has been wound, you can tell, recently.
Nothing here feels abandoned.
In fact, it feels expected.
As you walk into the room, you see two doors that are closed
behind the chalkboard.
As mentioned, there are coat hooks and a little like student
seating area, often to the left and right.
The wall is lined along the left and to the right.
There are five hooks all empty along a very similar
wooden coat rack.
Do we hear any noise?
Like, is there any sound as if there are students in a
classroom or does it seem abandoned?
You don't hear anything from further inside the building.
Not like a switch just hitting a kid.
Just, oh my God, it's from a different time.
They were really, they were punishment.
Wait a moment.
And then you hear, ow, stop, God, why?
I wasn't here before, but somebody recommended it.
I'm sorry.
And then they yes-ended it.
No, you don't hear anybody screaming.
Little Timmy's been here for centuries without rain getting
switched yet.
Dumbgeons and Dragons is a D&D actual play podcast and I'm
your Dungeon Master Russ More, he, him.
Also with me today is Amy More as Alydin, she, her.
You just wait until I turn this bucket into a bucket of
holding.
Carla Maxted is Bonwyn Everbane, she, her.
I hit control F.
Tom Laird is Kavlaran Goldweave, he, him.
Nobody thought there was Russ.
And Kyle Clasett is Bizard the Wizard, he, him.
You might be right.
Let's go.
Dumbgeons and Dragons is a Patreon supported show made
possible by listeners like you.
Join us today at patreon.com slash dumb dragon cast and get
a free seven day trial to try everything out over there.
And now fuck it.
Let's play.
You don't hear anything as you enter the building.
How about smell?
Musty or like exactly the smell of a school that seems
to never change?
It does smell exactly like a school that's never changed.
It smells, it doesn't smell musty, there's no dust.
It looks as if this entire area has been fairly well kept up.
Like if you were to walk into the school back in
Vintersmouth, you'd say that's, you know, they were
expecting students tomorrow kind of thing.
Sure.
Okay.
Well, perhaps the attendant just needs to be summoned.
Going to ring the bell, see if there's like a little
hammer, it's got a clapper on it or something.
Yeah.
We had a good experience with the other ones.
So let's just, let's get them out here.
Let's get them out here.
Brazard, you walk up to the bell and give it a ring and
it rings this clear tone that you hear echo throughout the
entire space and several long seconds later, you hear a
second bell that answers from somewhere, what sounds like
below.
Doesn't sound like an echo though.
It sounds like a response.
Alastair looks at you and says, I think that came from
underneath us.
I mean, that makes sense.
The other guy was underneath, right?
So this guy might be the paper guy.
Yeah.
Right.
Do you guys think we should just wait here?
Like, that's what the sign says to do.
Oh, should we hang up our jackets?
I think it's a good idea.
Actually, it crossed my mind just instinctively from going
to school.
So look at you, you thinking about how to act in the
school.
I've been there a couple of times.
Yeah.
I'll take off my jacket and hang it up.
My two coats.
You take up all of them and leave none for anybody else?
Everybody who is wearing a coat, I assume everybody goes
and hangs up their jacket.
And every hook along the way has a carefully engraved
brass nameplate.
Yours, the ones that you're hanging up on, appear empty.
There's no engraving on them.
That'd just be weird if it had our names on it already.
I know.
Did you imagine?
It seems odd.
Do you think they expect visitors often?
Well, who is they?
There's not supposed to be anybody here.
That's true.
But nothing about this place in this town has seemed normal.
Can I do like a general vibe check?
Because for Carla, this seems fine.
Again, all based on that other attendant guy being chill.
Yes, absolutely.
It's the only reference point we have.
Even though we're in an abandoned town.
But it's like, this feels kind of OK.
It seems less scary than the portal door in the middle
of the empty lake.
I would take an abandoned, maybe not abandoned, school
any day over a random portal in a dried up lake.
There doesn't seem to be any immediate danger.
You can just look at anything you want.
So there's the the chalkboard, the coat hooks, the brass bell.
The floor looks immaculately clean.
What would you like to look at?
I am actually fine to hang up my coat.
And did it seem like one of those doors was closer
to where the sound was coming from below?
It did sound like it was coming up from beneath you.
So either either door at this point
doesn't really
it doesn't lean one way or the other right now for you.
What do you say, guys?
Both at the same time?
Cthulhu style.
If you don't get that reference, listen to Call of Cthulhu.
It's on our Facebook page.
And we make some really good decisions.
There's some choices we're made, absolutely.
Interesting choices.
Bizard, I will point out for you as you're running the bell
that the brass bell itself looks like it was recently polished.
And as you rang it, it did feel like warm to the touch.
OK. Yeah, I was curious if there's been some bells in the past.
I feel like there was something in the Feywild we were in there.
I was wondering if it was reminiscent of that or had that kind of essence to it.
Great question.
Trying to remember those bells specifically.
Nothing that gives you
nothing aside from it being a bell,
being the spaces looks like it's kind of out of place within the town.
Nothing that would specifically draw you back.
No runes, no banjo man kind of paraphernalia, nothing like that.
Not banjo man.
Banjo man is just standing there.
That was the second follow up question.
OK, does it have banjo man's face on it?
Like, is this a banjo man bell?
Is there a banjo on it?
Exactly. Yeah, it's a banjo bell.
Never look at banjos the same again.
I'm going to I'm going to take the response and say, you know,
I think we could go ahead and head on in.
I think so, too.
We should go to the office.
Well, that's where the visitors go.
That is. That's true.
That's where the but there's nothing labeled office, right?
We just see two doors.
Yeah, there's nothing, nothing indicating as you specify.
OK, well, maybe it's this one.
And I point right.
You might be right. Open the door.
Are you opening both or just the one?
Just just the one on the right.
So as as you all step towards the the door on the right.
Bonwyn, you kind of take the lead.
Alydin, I assume you can follow pretty quickly.
Cav, you and Alastair are farthest back in this room.
And as your friends reach the door and go to open it,
you see that the chalkboard appears to be like cleaning itself.
And a new phrase is being written on in chalk,
even though the chalk remains on the sill and it says attendance is ready.
And as you approach the door, the double doors,
you hear them unlock with a soft metallic click.
So did anyone notice the chalkboard has a new message on it now?
Oh, yeah, that's a look there.
That's how attendance is ready.
Attendance is ready.
Like haunted school. Is that is that what's going on?
I mean, we've seen things being written on paper.
Yeah. A lot recently.
Charmed, right? Just magic-y shit.
Just just magic-y shit.
Yeah. Yeah. Magic.
Everything about the Weeping Archive I've read is just
it's just littered with magic-y shit.
I mean, like, actually, there's something to be said here
when it comes to the potential for illusions.
Is. You have to question what you see as we move further into this.
I am giving this lesson to myself,
and I think it's important for everybody to hear it like.
Don't trust what you see.
Give it a second look.
OK, that seems like a really good idea.
Thank you. Just a good life thing.
Yeah. Yeah.
Still going to open the door.
Is it a door? Is it a door?
Is it a door? It's a mimic.
Fuck. Jesus, no.
Do we check for traps?
No, you didn't check for traps. No, we did not.
But yes, it is a it is a door and it opens into a chamber.
And as you kind of take a half step in there,
first one through Bonwyn, you were leading the way.
You look to your left
and this room, both doors open into this room.
Oh, the chamber is lined from floor to ceiling
with narrow brass tracks.
Hundreds of carved wooden nameplates rest within them.
Above the wall, five headings have been carved into the stone.
Present, absent, excused,
reassigned and preserved.
There are no desks in this room, no chairs.
No people. Only names.
So the names themselves
appear on the wall straight ahead of you as you walk in there.
As you step in, there's also a teacher's podium,
a leather attendance ledger and a brass, a polished brass bell
also sit on on this on this podium as you enter.
Another thing you notice as you step in
is that this room feels like a well treated voicing booth.
Like the sound of your footsteps, the sound of your voices
like quickly dissipates.
There's not a lot of echo in this room.
Oh, Alydin definitely runs up to the podium
and starts just like mocking teachers.
I mean, settle down class, settle down.
Who am I? And then I realized none of you go to my school.
I'm like, it's true.
Didn't take long for Alydin to turn on the whole school idea.
Hey, after we just got it started, the kids are already complaining.
Man. Yeah. Baby steps.
You're right. We got him in the building.
That's what counts.
I want to look over at the the present, absent, excused, reassigned
and preserved. How many like what's the number of people listed under each?
Mm hmm. And that's on the chalkboard.
It's on the roof.
Yeah, it's like there's like it's up on the ceiling.
Yes. So, yeah, the the the actual headings of them
up here above the wall.
And then the car there are, yes,
chamber lined from floor to ceiling with these narrow brass tracks.
So all along the wall in front of you are the are the tracks
with these wooden nameplates that looks like you could manipulate,
like a physical filing system that.
Yeah. Yeah.
Like how you put a nameplate on a door. Exactly.
I was imagining I hit not going to lie.
I was like tracks everywhere.
I wonder if there are cars with control left with just hot wheel tracks.
Yeah. That's right.
So this is a manually done thing.
Yes, exactly. So, yeah, you could if you if you were so inclined,
you could slide them off, move names around and do it that way.
So there are, as I mentioned, hundreds of names make
what's going to be a good one here.
Make a laugh for us.
I said I'd like to control F.
You hit control and I don't know.
Alladin, like what do we?
Yeah. What do we actually get to do?
Yeah, you begin to you begin to look through them
and you take some time.
And there are infinite names that you don't recognize.
But if you begin to stand out
more specifically to you, Bonwyn,
you see the name Malin Everbane with a denotion of craft
underneath her name.
And she is under preserved.
You see Heron Linger, which is a name that you've heard
in other documentation so far,
with the denotion of agricultural under reassigned.
You see Loris Harrison
civic studies under excused.
You see Elric River
with the denotion of surveying under preserve.
Junel Foyson observation
under present and A.
Grieves maintenance
also under present and cav.
I mean, the name Harrison has jumped out to you.
Sure. But also you see one that isn't a name.
It just says pending.
Am I able to get more information on that?
There's not really any more specific information at this point,
but it stands out because everything has a name,
has one of these several classifications,
I guess you could call them.
And this one does not.
Just pending.
I would like to flip through the ledger,
the leather ledger that's at my podium,
as I am pretending to be.
Sure. As you step up to it and it's on,
you're flipping through in the final completed page,
kind of where this book ended off.
You see that it reads attendance complete,
dismissal complete, transition complete
and continuity maintained.
The signature line on it remains blank.
As you flip back through,
you see all of these pages filled out very similarly,
all signed off in a signature that you can't really pick.
But then you can't tell what the name is based on the signature.
It's pretty sloppy.
Can I pick up the book?
Yeah. Yeah. Yeah.
Just going to take this with me.
Pick it up. You have it. Oh, yeah.
Well, you know, just in case.
Hey, you're carrying a bucket.
Why not put some stuff in it? Right.
Absolutely. You just wait
till I turn this bucket into a bucket of holding.
It's got to happen at some point.
Are our names up there?
You spend some time looking through them
and you don't see any of your names up there.
And it was only the one pending, right, Russ?
Correct. After a few moments
of kind of painstakingly going through as many names as you as you can,
you hear some soft footsteps in this room.
There's doors off to the left and to the right.
They are closed.
You hear some soft footsteps off to the right.
In that time, do we do a quick ballpark of, you know, count,
count across and down and do a quick times table here in the school room
and figure out about how many names are on on this bad boy?
Yes, you could have done that roughly.
There's some spots missing in, but between four and five hundred names.
Hmm.
Damn. More than I thought.
I'm glad I asked and I was picturing like 50.
I want to go and slide one of the nameplates out.
OK, or try to slide one of the nameplates.
I'm going to go ahead and try to hide as somebody is walking up on us.
Sure. So the only place to really hide yourself
is either on either side of the door or behind the podium.
There's no desks, no curtains, no anything else in this space.
So while you're determining where you want to hide,
I will tell you what happens.
So you just go to take it off then?
Yeah, I just want to go like just slide it just because I'm perusing
and I'm curious and it looks like like it's a manual thing you could do.
So why wouldn't I?
Do you go for any of the names that I listed or just can I reach them?
Which names can I reach?
Yeah, you'd be able to reach
any of the names that I that I listed.
There are all within your reach.
I will I will look at the only name
that I would recognize would be Everbane.
Sure. So I want to slide Everbane's
around and take a take a look see at that.
So, yeah, you slide it out
and you can hold it as a well carved and crafted solid piece of wood.
It feels like a hard wood, perhaps an oak, a nice shellac on it.
I sniff it, I go oak, I think. Yeah, this is yeah.
And as you do that,
Bizard, where have you hidden?
I'm going to go from behind the door.
OK, the door opens and in steps
someone who appears familiar.
It looks exactly like Joe, the hall monitor.
OK, he steps into the room.
He's carrying a clipboard.
It's carrying a clipboard.
Takes a few steps in,
looks at everybody else in the room, not Bizard,
because you're behind the door, but looks at everybody else
and offers what appears to be the smallest, courteous nod.
Hi, Joe.
He looks down towards you, nods again,
looks back to his clipboard and then carries on.
Continues walking to the door on the opposite side of the room.
Oh, I want to go like right in front of him and be like,
Hey, do you remember me?
He looks down.
There's no response.
He takes kind of a half step back as you as you as you get in front of him.
It appears to just be, you know, protecting you from being stepped on
more than anything, not startled or scared to me or anything.
Yeah. It turns and regards everybody else in the room
and then puts a puts a gentle hand on your shoulder
and just kind of guides you to the side.
And he continues to move forward towards the door.
Rude. Towards where we came from.
No, sorry.
So you came in the double doors.
There are two doors left and right.
He came out of the right
and is moving across to the other door to the left.
See, he's carrying a clipboard, he said.
Yeah. Yeah.
Hey, am I on your clipboard?
And he's still walking and I'm just like, yeah, he's still walking.
He opens the door and kind of guards the door.
Has my status changed?
Looks down at you, offers a similar nod,
walks into this other room and then closes the door. Rude.
Welcome to the middle, everybody.
We're here.
Whiplash in the middle.
So glad to see you here.
That's that's so glad to see you.
Glad to see you.
Glad, glad and glad.
We're making words.
Yeah, that's that's all we're doing here.
This is how language evolves.
Everybody test out a new word on the show tonight.
That way we can really just get take advantage of this.
And what do we do?
He wants to transition, but he just said take advantage of.
And now it's like, no, yeah, that's not a segue I'm willing to take.
It was a weird call to action.
We would have stopped you.
We weren't going to let you do that to yourself.
There's us.
Take advantage of a free trial of Patreon.
I knew there was a way.
It just didn't work like that way.
So, yeah, we do have that seven day free trial.
Come give us a shot.
I mean, listen to 400 episodes, but give us one more try.
Put us in, coach.
I believe you can do it.
There's some other things.
There's another show.
If you plan this free trial around the first Tuesday of the month,
you can come join us for it.
For I was going to say a gook hang, but we're not calling it that anymore
because it doesn't make sense.
But basically, you get to, like, chill with us.
Maybe we play a game.
Maybe we have a deep conversation about the future and life and metaphysics,
or we just make dick jokes.
I don't know. Anything could happen.
Any direction. Yeah.
And you don't find out if you join us on Patreon,
patreon.com slash dumb dragon cast, where when you are a patron,
you get an episode dedicated to you like you.
OK, you ready for it, guys?
Yep. It's OK.
One cutie per enjoy.
Thank you. One cutie per enjoy.
I did some quick Googling and PRN is a kind of nurse.
Oh, it's one cutie.
Professional one cutie PRN joy.
Professional registered nurse Joy.
Could be that. Are you Joy?
Nurse Joy, like from Pokemon.
Joy the cutie nurse.
Guys, I think we're getting closer to this.
I think we maybe are solving this mystery.
Now, if you're wondering, OK, well, they only guessed really like one thing.
And then they made this leap.
We recorded a different middle for our patrons over there
where we ran through several options.
Oh, many options.
We ran through a lot of options. Some appropriate or some not.
So if you are one cutie nurse joy, PRN joy,
and you haven't listened to that one, you should go listen to that one
because there's oh, yeah, there's ad free throughout a lot of options.
And we're still desperate for you to dip into the discord
and just like let us know. Yeah.
Because we love you.
And we want to know more about you, including your mysterious origin story.
Absolutely.
And know more about all that ad free stuff for us.
Because if you're listening to this middle, you've got ads, baby.
You do. And sure, you can skip them.
This is an ad for Patreon. It is.
Oh, my God. You're in a middle.
You're in an ad. We're advertising to you right now.
But over there, consume ad free and early.
And early. And carbo bill.
There are benefits. Yeah.
Join us, won't you?
We want to see you over there.
Patreon dot com slash.
You saved time.
Dragon cast.
Google gobble.
I just had to say it between all of the one of us.
Yeah, I know.
Two things got a bit evil there at the end.
It's not evil. I swear.
The website is not patreon dot com slash one of us.
Dumb one of us.
No, no, it's not that.
You'll never get there.
Dumb of us.
You might get some of us.
Oh, dumb of us.
That's very OK.
Letting you get back to the episode now.
Love you. Bye bye.
Hmm. Yeah, not as forthcoming.
Hey, I don't think that's the same.
Not as chatty.
Joe's twin is like, yeah, I don't know.
Evil twin.
Evil. That's a big jump.
Do you think so?
No, I'm just being silly.
Rude Joe.
We can go.
We can go where it came from and see what it could have been doing.
OK. That is true.
Hey, Bonwyn, do you want this?
And I I hand her the plaque with her.
It's her name on it.
And I had been so nervous when Alydin was taking it down,
but I didn't, you know, she needs to explore the world on her own.
I would be like, don't.
Um, but I don't know.
I feel like until we know what's going on, maybe we should just put it back.
And then if everything's cool, it would be a pretty dope souvenir.
That would be pretty cool.
OK, I'll put it back.
I saw it back in exactly where I found it.
Exactly where you found it.
Exactly where I found it.
OK, you slide it in exactly where you found it.
And then you're going towards the door where this
where it came from, where it came out of Joe, a look alike.
OK, 2.0 Rude Joe.
Cav, you're still kind of looking, trying to determine,
you know, names on the board and that sort of thing.
You see Alydin put hers back and everybody's making their way towards the door.
And as you take a few steps away, that pending plaque,
you see it shift from kind of this neutral position,
not really in under any column.
You see it slide across the wall and it lands under present.
Huh?
Uh, pending is now present.
Oh, and I don't think their name is right.
Fair, fair.
That's very good, Alydin.
Thanks.
Um, do we I mean.
Because you didn't do you think that is that you?
Do you think you have status now because you're present?
Because you didn't were unknown before, right?
In the basement at the other school, me.
Yeah, you know, so you think that's me.
You think I'm pending.
I don't know.
I mean, you were pending and now you're here and pending.
It just seems like kind of a coincidence.
I'm the only one out of all of us.
You did just ask Joe who actually attends school.
So I should be the least mystery.
I'm just saying.
Yeah, that's fair.
Yeah, you have a point.
Russ, can I roll an insight check on Alistair?
Sure.
Just see how his whole vibe is going.
Yeah, seems pretty awake for a while yet.
And now he's present.
He has been awake for a suspiciously long time.
He has been suspiciously awake.
Suspiciously conscious.
Actually, it's been like 10 seconds.
We've walked into a room.
That's all we've done.
Well, no, I fucked around.
Pretended to be a teacher.
We looked around.
500 names.
We found Joe 2.0 when he found us.
Yeah, Alistair, give me an insight roll.
17 plus 5, so 22.
OK, I mean, you've been paying attention to the wall,
but as things are changing, you look at Alistair.
And Alistair, he's doing very similar to you,
looking very pensively at all of the names on the board.
You've seen him walk over to the door
where this automaton has walked into,
and it seems like the door itself was locked.
He turns back, and he's got his hand on his head,
and he says, schools record who's present, right?
That's what this is.
It feels like the attendance room.
But he looks back towards the wall.
They don't usually decide who belongs here, right?
He looks equally as confused as everybody else around him.
Everybody on this wall, there's names here
that seem familiar from writings that I've seen,
but he looks up to the ceiling, which
seems like it goes on forever.
There's so many people.
And what happens when somebody's preserved?
Yeah, great question.
And I mean, even reassigned, do we
think that means they just went to a different school?
They just went to Vindersmith or somewhere else?
I don't know.
And where is Janelle and Reeves?
They're here.
That's what it says, is here is not the archive.
The door outside is the archive, right?
And he goes.
Yeah, you're the expert.
You should know.
He goes back to the doors to the out.
The doors behind you haven't closed or anything.
You can still see out.
And he goes to the front door, and he looks out.
And Alydin, you hear a little click on Malin's name.
It's like just slightly off center,
and it clicks back into place.
And at that same moment, and as Alistair kind of goes out
to the front door there, a low vibration
passes beneath everyone's feet.
The bell below rings once again.
And Alistair calls.
He's like, hey, I think the door is brightening.
I run over.
Something new is happening.
Want to see?
You all quickly run outside, and you
catch just the tail end of it.
But what he sees is the stone frame to the doorway
appears to sharpen in picture and becomes brighter
than it was before.
You see now more than just the door,
a hallway begin to appear visible only
for a few seconds behind the door.
You can see walls beginning to form.
Then it begins to fade once again.
And Alistair stares toward the doorway.
And he's, something about this place
is certainly tied to that door.
And something we're doing.
Was it the bell?
The bell made it brighter?
The wall clicked.
I'm going to go ring the bell.
What do you mean?
Oh, yeah, there was a click.
What do you mean the wall clicked?
Like where I took out.
And replace the name?
Yeah, I guess I didn't do it good enough.
But it went back in and it clicked.
And you were like, oh, the door.
OK, I'm sure there's something we have to do.
We have to go check some of these other rooms, I think.
Well, it was MAlydin.
They were preserved.
So maybe it has to do with preserved energy in a way
or something in a power sense.
Can you guys watch?
And I'll go move it again, maybe.
OK.
See if it happens again.
Well, don't go alone.
I'll come with you.
What if you locked in there?
Thanks.
Do you do the same name or a different name or doesn't?
Probably the same name.
I want to recreate the same circumstances.
Take it out, put it in.
Wait.
Shake it all about.
Do the hokey pokey.
That's right.
Take it out.
You examine it.
See if there's any sort of mechanism on it
that maybe was missed.
It's just a wooden plate.
They could have clicked, yeah.
You slide it back in.
Again, it rattles a little bit sliding in there.
You leave it for a few moments.
And then because it's slightly off center,
clicks back into place.
OK, click.
Did it do anything?
Everybody outside sees just the not quite as bright
as it was before.
But similarly, the doorway brightens again.
That hallway appears for a few seconds and then disappears.
What if there's more names that
need to be put in to build up a whole?
OK.
I look around for a stack of these guys.
I don't know.
There's nothing.
Yeah, because the back of the book
said that attendance dismissal and transition
are all complying.
Real quick, Malin was a crafter.
And when we put their name on, it builds something.
So let's find other crafters and see if attaching them
builds out more of the realm.
Interesting.
I like it.
OK.
Run back in with Bonwyn.
Start looking for names.
Start looking for more crafters.
Yeah, you find, well, I mean,
there's at least 100 names that kind of fall
under that craft capability under different columns.
You grab a few.
Who's standing guard, so to speak, watching the door?
I'll be there.
OK.
Bizarre, you and Alistair are at the door
watching the fading in and out from the middle
of the lake bed.
And everybody is analyzing and moving
all of these name plates around.
I figure we're moving them to the preserved column,
just because that's where her name is, right?
That's where her name is.
Yeah.
That's the only one I remember.
Let's try that.
Yeah.
So how many names total do you want to move?
The names themselves aren't.
Let's move one at a time and click them into place
and see if anything happens.
Sure.
This is a controlled scientific experiment.
I really feel like we're being very methodical
about this.
You grab one from under the reassigned column
and move it into the preserved column.
You stand and wait the same few seconds.
Goes a little longer.
And after you've given up on the same experience,
you see the name itself begin to vibrate.
And it slides itself across the track.
The track itself almost gives the appearance
that it's extending out and then slides across back
to the reassigned column and snaps back
into place over there.
OK.
Did anything happen to the door?
Nothing out here.
What if we mix up the ones in this row?
OK.
Like everybody in preserved, move them up and down.
Move them around.
I feel like this is one of those picture puzzles
where you have to move the tile.
Right.
And there's the one empty space and you have to.
Yes.
Exactly.
Bizard, you look back and you
see everyone rearranging this column
as high as they can reach, moving names around.
And on the chalkboard, you see
that it's changed since you guys left that room initially.
It now says attendance accepted.
Everybody else, as you finish reorganizing these names,
you wait about the same amount of time
as that secondary name that you had tried.
And then you see these names begin to slide out of place
and reorganize themselves within the wall
until they all finally click.
And then Bizard, back out in the lake bed,
you see that doorway begin to glow again.
And you see that hallway similar to before,
similar to the first time that Alistair called you out.
And then after a few seconds, begins to fade back down.
And it gets like it fades the most it's faded so far.
How about that?
That do anything?
Yeah, I think grab the coats.
I think we need to get in there.
We have to get in there?
Go in the fading door?
I have like eight more experiments
I want to do on this wall.
We didn't even go through any of the other doors.
I don't know.
If Bizard says we need to go, I think we kind of need to go.
I honestly don't know.
Oh, OK.
As you guys are having this back and forth,
everybody who's primarily in the building,
you hear that low rumble again beneath your feet.
What if there's a dragon in the basement?
What if there's a dragon in the basement
and it has to get free?
And we're the only ones who know that it's down there.
And then we'll have a pet dragon.
Alydin, the door that the door.
Fuck you, Kyle.
Could be a dragon.
I won't interrupt that back and forth.
The door where the Joe figure came out,
not where he went in, where he came out,
you hear the faint.
Actually, what's your passive perception?
10.
I'm a G2.
I'm an adult.
OK, I'll I'll take that.
OK, hold on.
Never mind.
You know, that's fine.
Tom, what's your.
No, it's OK.
It's not it's anything you hear.
You're not entirely sure from where you hear
a similar faint click, similar to when the the doors
then to this room unlock.
Is anything happening now?
I assume it's going to affect the door.
It's fine.
I don't see anything changing up.
Alistair stay here.
Keep an eye on it.
And I'm going to head back inside to talk with everyone.
OK, yeah, yeah, of course.
I'll just stand.
I'm going to ring the bell.
I want to see if anything happens.
It's the only other thing that happened kind
of around that accepted.
As you walk in, he Alistair sits down on the steps
kind of coming up and you see him lean on one
of the stone railways.
You're ringing the bell as bizarre as you're coming back
in bond when you're reaching for the bell, you ring it.
Nothing immediately happens.
Five seconds, maybe more pass than you hear again
from beneath the Academy.
You hear a single bell answer from somewhere below.
However, unlike before, this reply
is followed by the sound of enormous gears
shifting into place.
The machinery continues for several seconds
before falling silent again.
Oops.
Alistair, anything with the door there?
Huh, what?
No.
Sorry.
No, no, nothing with the door.
It's the same.
Same fading.
We shouldn't leave the narcoleptic.
What if he falls asleep on the door
and then falls through the door?
Exactly.
I didn't even think that could happen.
I'm not touching the door yet.
Not until we're done looking at the school.
You were sleeping, weren't you?
I just got a little sleepy.
I was just resting my eyes.
It's not your fault that you're sleepy.
It's just we should know better than to have
you be the person that needs to observe a thing.
That's on us.
That's fair.
I think that's on us.
I take full responsibility.
I think Alydin's dragon is a mechanical dragon.
And I look down at, oh, fuck me.
Cogsworth Quackerton?
Quackington.
Quackleton.
Cogsworth Quackleton.
It's been since February.
And I go, oh, a Cogsworth dragon.
And that's where we're in today's episode.
Just run bust through that other door.
Dumbgeons and Dragons, season four, episode 62,
starring Amy More as Alydin, Carla
Maxted as Bonwyn Everbane, Tom Laird as Kavlaran Goldweave,
Kyle Claset as Bizard the Wizard,
and Russ More as your dungeon master.
Dialogue editing and sound design of today's episode
is by Russ More.
Our community manager is Jessica Babyok.
Music is from Epidemic Sound.
And sound effects are from Epidemic Sound, Boom Library,
and Sound Ideas.
Our amazing cover art is by Matt Garbutt.
A huge thank you to our supporting producers,
Gabriel Lynch, Jessica Babyok,
Angur Rangkirzan, Perry Matey,
Count Waterflame, Jacob Madden, Old School Gamer D,
Craig Zeiss, and L.A. Branton.
Dumbgeons and Dragons is a Patreon-supported show.
Because of our Patreon supporters,
we get to keep telling bigger, weirder,
more heartfelt stories in this world we love.
And honestly, that's something
we will never take for granted.
Join us today at patreon.com slash dumb dragon cast,
and help us tell the stories that you want to hear.
We hope to see you over there.
Have a great week, and we'll talk to you soon.
This is recording.
Check one, check two, still recording
with decent levels, okay, good.
Happiness.
Say that again.
Okay.
You all step up to the, oh,
and if anybody has any notes from the previous one,
I've changed the entire entry narration to the school.
So disregard anything from the door opens.
I know, Tom, that was the one note you took.
Out of my mind.
I have to throw so many notes out now.
I'm worried specifically about you Tom, I don't know.
Guilty as charged.
Dumbgeons and Dragons is a Dumb Dragons production.